Sometimes you want to agree that the other side is right about something.
有时你想同意对方在某事上是对的。
Whether you're having a regular conversation or a debate right maybe a part of what they're saying is
无论您是在进行定期对话还是辩论，他们所说的部分内容可能是
correct but they're not seeing the whole picture and you still think you're right about the whole picture.
正确，但他们没有看到全貌，您仍然认为您对全貌是正确的。
Or maybe you want to agree with one point but say that maybe that point is not as important as this
或者，也许你想同意一个观点，但说也许那个观点没有这个重要
point.
观点。
Whatever we need to be able to concede the point.
无论我们需要能够承认这一点。
Sometimes that means we need to be able to show other people that we agree a little bit.
有时这意味着我们需要能够向其他人表明我们有点同意。
We agree but we need to say usually.
我们同意，但我们通常需要说。
But OK we're not going to look at three expressions we can use to say OK what you said just now.
但是好的，我们不打算看三个表达方式，我们可以用它来表示你刚才所说的话。
That's probably true.
这可能是真的。
Maybe that's right.
也许这是对的。
However and then make another point that hopefully disagrees with with that point or shows that maybe
然而，然后提出另一点，希望不同意这一点或表明可能
it doesn't matter if they're correct whatever.
不管它们是否正确都没有关系。
OK so let's look at these three phrases.
好的，让我们看看这三个短语。
There is no denying that alcoholism is a problem but OK so you're saying alcoholism is a major problem.
不可否认，酗酒是一个问题，但好吧，所以你说酗酒是一个主要问题。
OK.
好的。
Well I don't disagree with that.
好吧，我不同意这一点。
There's no denying that alcoholism is a problem.
不可否认，酗酒是一个问题。
But OK so one side says we have to do something about this.
但是好的，所以一方说我们必须对此做点什么。
Decreasing the age is a terrible idea because it will increase this.
减少年龄是一个糟糕的主意，因为它会增加年龄。
This major issue.
这个重大问题。
Well there's no denying that alcoholism is a problem.
那么不可否认，酗酒是一个问题。
But is this the best solution I think.
但这是我认为最好的解决方案。
Blah blah blah.
等等等等等等。
OK.
好的。
So I'm giving the point to the person who said it.
所以我把重点放在说这句话的人身上。
No disagreement.
没有异议。
It also is a way to help define where the agreement and disagreements are.
这也是一种帮助确定协议和分歧在哪里的方法。
And this can be a really good way to clarify your point and clarify your position or your case or your
这可能是澄清你的观点和澄清你的立场或你的案子或你的
argument while you're right that many deaths have been caused by underage drinking.
虽然你是对的，但争论很多死亡是由未成年人饮酒造成的。
OK.
好的。
So this would be on the other side.
所以这将在另一边。
Now maybe the other side has used the isn't it true.
现在也许对方已经使用了，不是吗。
And I want to admit that it is but then I'm going to say something else while you're right that many
我想承认是的，但是我要说点别的，而你是对的
deaths have been caused by underage drinking.
未成年人饮酒导致死亡。
I agree with that point.
我同意这一点。
I also feel or I think.
我也觉得或者我觉得。
OK.
好的。
And then say something else.
然后说点别的。
I don't know what that point would be.
我不知道那个点会是什么。
But the point is to learn this expression in this way to agree to that point and then move on and focus
但关键是要以这种方式学习这种表达方式以同意这一点，然后继续前进并集中注意力
on something else.
在别的事情上。
This can be a really good way to focus on another point even though that point is a very good point
这可能是专注于另一点的一个非常好的方法，即使该点是一个非常好的点
and not really answer it directly or spend a lot of time talking about that point.
而不是真正直接回答或花大量时间谈论这一点。
The other one is I'll admit that alcoholism hasn't declined much but so one person has said well listen
另一种是我承认酗酒并没有减少太多，但有人说很好听
the drinking age at 21 it's not working very well because alcoholism is the same.
21 岁的饮酒年龄它效果不佳，因为酗酒是一样的。
See.
看。
Well I'll admit that alcoholism hasn't changed that much but but then I can make another point either
好吧，我承认酗酒并没有太大变化，但是我也可以提出另一点
a point that contradicts or disagrees with what you just said or to show that maybe something else is
与您刚才所说的相矛盾或不同意的观点，或者表明可能还有其他内容
more important or to kind of shift focus and change the topics a little bit and focus on something else
更重要的是转移焦点并稍微改变主题并专注于其他事情
a stronger point that I have.
我有一个更强的观点。
So this is sort of a way to fight against some of the phrases that we learned earlier on in the lesson.
所以这是一种对抗我们在课程前面学到的一些短语的方法。
Very useful as well.
也非常有用。
OK.
好的。
So these are the ways that we can first make points make arguments and poke holes in another person's
所以这些是我们可以首先提出论点并在另一个人的观点中戳洞的方法
case.
案子.
And then also how we can fight against or avoid really focusing on the points that other people have
然后还有我们如何对抗或避免真正关注其他人的观点
made.
制成。
So hopefully these three ways of giving the other side a point come in handy or are useful to you when
所以希望这三种给对方点数的方法能派上用场或对你有用
you're disagreeing with someone who has a very good point.
你不同意一个有很好观点的人。
Next we're going to talk about how we can actually debate a topic.
接下来，我们将讨论如何实际辩论一个话题。